Kelly Ann Marshall

Web Development + Web Design + Print Design + Photography

BFA Photography, MSc Information Technology (Merit)

+44 (0)7906 117 249 kelly_ann_marshall@yahoo.com

https://kellyannmarshall.github.io

Summary

Talented frontend developer and designer with over 30 years of professional experience who is self-motivated, client-centric, creative, insightful and versatile. Adept at innovating user experience for web applications. Exceptional interpersonal skills and is efficient, organised, resourceful, flexible, reliable and willing to listen and contribute with clients and team members. Available for contract and permanent positions based in Glasgow City Centre or 100% remote.

Skills

- HTML(5)
- CSS(3) / SASS / LESS
- JavaScript / ES6 / jQuery
- Angular / Vue.js
- · Node / Webpack
- Docker / AWS / Jenkins
- · Git / Bitbucket / SVN
- Jasmine / Karma / Jest / Cypress
- Mapbox / OpenLayers

- Jekyll / Joomla / Wordpress / Eleventy
- Responsive Web Design
- · Wireframing / Prototyping
- Progressive Enhancement
- W3C Standards & Accessibility
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Balsamiq / Figma / Adobe XD
- Cross-Browser Compatibility
- Google Analytics

Professional Experience

Front-End Developer (Nov 2022 - Present)

Beeks Group, Glasgow, Scotland

Technologies: Angular, Typescript, D3.js, Jasmine, Storybook, Docker, Bitbucket, Jira

- Working as part of an internal development team on the client-side code for Beeks Partner Portal
- This is a self-service portal application built in Angular that helps customers automate the creation of server infrastructure, log support requests and view server usage analytics built with D3.js charts

Senior Developer (Aug 2020 - Jun 2022)

Idox Group (acquired thinkWhere in Oct 2021), Glasgow, Scotland

Technologies: Angular, Typescript, RxJS, OpenLayers, Python, Flask, Bootstrap, Cypress, AWS, pgAdmin, Docker, Terraform, IIS, Figma, AdobeXD, Balsamiq, Git, Jira

- Worked as part of an agile development team with a focus on design and UI development of groundMapper, a fully-featured cloud service GIS data application
- Wireframing, UI design and front-end development of advanced search functionality, split-screen map / data views and bespoke forestry data management features
- Development and delivery of new admin features for groundMapper including permissions and account, project and user management
- UI design and front-end development of Eurogeographics Open Maps for Europe website, a resource for official European map, geospatial and land information

Previous Experience

UI Developer (Aug 2018 - Feb 2020)

VisitScotland, Edinburgh, Scotland

Front-End Developer (Aug 2017 - May 2018)

Peninsula Business Services, Glasgow, Scotland

Front-End Developer (Feb 2014 - May 2017)

Arnold Clark, Glasgow, Scotland

Web Content Officer (Oct 2012 - Nov 2013)

University of Glasgow, Glasgow, Scotland

Web Developer / Research Assistant (Oct 2011 - Sep 2012)

University of Glasgow, Glasgow, Scotland

Print and Web Designer (Feb 2008 - Sept 2010)

Admit One, New York, NY

Print and Web Designer (Nov 2002 - Nov 2007)

Henry M. Jackson Foundation for the Advancement of Military Medicine, Rockville, MD

Print and Web Designer (Feb 1999 - Dec 2000)

LADO International College, Washington, DC

Advertising Designer (Jun 1996 - Jan 1999)

Channing Bete, South Deerfield, MA

Freelance Designer (May 1994 - May 1996)

New York, NY

Digital Retoucher (Jun 1993 - May 1994)

Digital Stock Connection, Rockville, MD

Education

Master of Science in Information Technology (Sep 2010 - Sep 2011)

University of Glasgow, Glasgow, Scotland

Emphasis: Programming in Java, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, XML, HTML, CSS, Django, Python, Multimedia Systems, Software Project Management, Information Systems and Databases

Dissertation: A web Interface for the purchase of live event tickets with interactive venue maps built with SVG, JavaScript, PHP and MySQL

Activities: Postgraduate Student Representative

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Photography (Sep 1989 - Jun 1993)

Maryland Institute, College of Art, Baltimore, Maryland

Emphasis: B&W and colour photography and development, film and video production, photochemistry, alternative photo processes, studio lighting, 2D design, computer illustration, painting, drawing, sculpture, art history and the history of photography